# BenVineyard

SR FULLSTACK SOFT WARE ENGINEER

# **HELLO WORLD!**

My name is Ben Lynn Vineyard IV and I am an 40 year old software engineer. I eat, drink, and sleep technology & software. I have been developing software professionally for over 20 years. I am passionate about what I do. confident I can deliver a viable customer product, and skilled enough to make it fly.



### EDUCATION -

**UNIVERSITY OF NORTH CAROLINA:** B5 - COMPUTER SCIENCE - 2001 I graduated with a bachelor of science degree in computer science in 2001. I possessed a 3.45 GPA.



## JOB EXPERIENCE—

### SR. SOFTWARE ARCHITECT:

### ARISTOCRAT | JULY 2019 - PRESENT

Shaping the new, distributed architecture for their casino systems software using RabbitMQ as an Enterprise service bus, .NET Core microservices, Docker & Kubernetes containerization, & GCP/Azure/AWS for cloud hosting.

### PRINCIPAL ENGINEER:

### KASEYA I JUNE 2018 - JULY 2019

Work with a variety of different languages, platforms, & frameworks such as Javascript, Typescript, Classic ASP, ASP,NET, C#, Entity Framework.

& SQL Server to maintain flagship VSA product offering.

### LEAD SOFTWARE DEVELOPER:

### STATION CASINOS | MAY 2016 - JUNE 2018

Led Agile teams developing software on the MEAN (MongoDB, Express, AngularJS, & Node.js) stack. Migrated legacy solutions off of the Microsoft stack such as WCF & ASP.NET. Containerized new, modern solutions using Docker & hosted in AWS & Azure. Maintained Sitecore based brochure websites via C# solutions.

### FOUNDER/CTO:

### BOTVANA | SEPT 2013 - FEB 2016

Created search engine optimized, Wordpress-based websites for clients of SEO-For-Lawyers.com. Consulted on a handful of angularJS front-end and nodeJS backend projects.

### SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER III:

### IGT | SEPT 2011 - JULY 2014

I wrote software and provided technical leadership for a team of engineers in both the US & China for IRC and CTA products from IGT's Advantage Suite. The core technologies were C#, WCF, & MSSOL.



Haywood Dr, Las Vegas, NV

702.913.6903

ben@benvineyard.com

www.benvineyard.com

www.github.com/benvineyard

**b** www.twitter.com/benvineyard

in linkedin.com/in/benvineyard

### SKILLS -

### PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

AngularJS/Angular/Ionic

Node.js

.NET/.NET Core/C#

React

SQL/NoSQL

### PERSONAL SKILLS

Communication

Teamwork

Creativity

Leadership

Management

# BenVineyard



## JOB EXPERIENCE-

### SR. SOFTWARE ENGINEER:

### COSMOPOLITAN LAS VEGAS I JULY 2010 - SEPT 2011

Architected & developed a queuing infrastructure for OpenTable vendor system, so that it could integrate from their SQL 2008 based database to both our hotel registration system and master data management system (DataFlux) using C# & MSSQL Service Broker.

### SR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPER:

### AIS | FEB 2010 - JULY 2010

Supported and maintained existing ASP.NET & Silverlight web applications with C# managed code-base. Architected & developed a cross-site casino progressive system using WCF 4.0 for message transport, Silverlight 4.0 for the user interface, and SQL 2008 for the data store.

### .NET SOFTWARE DEVELOPER:

### TECH RESULTS | APR 2009 - DEC 2009

Supported and maintained existing SSIS packages. Designed and authored Silverlight 3.0 web application with WCF back-end. Supported and maintained existing web application software comprised of ASP.NET front-ends and WCF back-ends.

#### PROGRAMMER/ANALYST:

### STATION CASINOS | MAY 2005 - APR 2009

Designed and wrote web and pc applications in VB6, VB.NET, & C#. Designed and implemented .NET-based service plug-ins in a Service Oriented Architecture (SOA). Designed and implemented C# web services and WCF services, exposing customer data on an AS400 IBM mainframe.

#### PROGRAMMER:

### SILVER STATE SCHOOLS CREDIT UNION | AUG 2003 - MAY 2005

Maintained & serviced an ASP/COM based online banking system. Co-Authored and maintained a VB.NET implementation of the aforementioned online banking system, written from the ground up. Co-Authored and maintained a PHP port of the .NET version of the

### SYSTEM ENGINEER:

### CAPCO ENTERPRISES | DEC 2001 - AUG 2003

Designed user interface for Player Rewards kiosk prototype for casinos. Originally targeted for Mandalay Bay Casino, using Adobe Photoshop & Illustrator. Created the web application for the kiosk prototype using a PHP based frontend and MySQL database backend. Engineered the Debian Linux based environment that the prototype operated in.

# BenVineyard

SR. FULLSTACK SOFT WARE ENGINEER



**CERTIFIED SCRUM DEVELOPER: SCRUM ALLIANCE 2013** 

Performed training through Scrum Alliance while employed at IGT and received my Certified Scrum Developer (CSD) certificate in 2013.

**CERTIFIED SCRUM MASTER: SCRUM ALLIANCE 2013** 

Performed training through Scrum Alliance while employed at IGT and received my Certified Scrum Master (CSM) certificate in 2013.